

Javad Adib







Full Stack PHP Developer, Software Engineer

Lives 15+ years with code and debugging as a programmer. Build 7+ infrastructure of multi-million dollar scalable projects from scratch. Earn valuable knowledge via collaboration with specialists. A learner who knows how to learn. Interested in negotiating and comprehending the customer. Extensive wisdom from eCommerce. Open-source enthusiast.

mr.javad.adib@gmail.com

+98-935-726-9759

Iran

v6.6.

Professional Experience

Founder, CEO, and Full Stack Developer

Jibres Iran

(4 years 6 months) 10/2017 - present

- Provide cloud infrastructure to 1,000+ businesses, integrated eCommerce solution with website, app, PoS software, CMS, CRM, accounting software, ticketing system, form builder.
- Joined the bug bounty program and introduced a new WAF that filters and monitors 99% of the attacks.
- Launched an automated app factory that generated a native android shopping app without coding in less than 10 minutes.

Founder, CEO, and Software Engineer

Ermile Iran

(4 years 8 months) 06/2015 - 12/2019

- Raised \$1M from Angel investor, spearheaded a 15 member crossfunctional team to create a Sarshomar that gained about 1M users just a month after launch.
- Constructed an educational management system that serves four organizations, 500,000+ students, 2,000+ teachers.
- Built Siftal UI framework, Dash as PHP framework with MVC pattern, 2x the development speed by consolidated SPA.

Web UI/UX Designer

Freelancer

(6 years 11 months) 09/2008 - 06/2015

- Designed, developed 40+ WordPress websites, user experience, communicated with dozens of customers, including universities, companies, government centers, celebrities.
- Strengthened negotiation skills, mastered sales skills, optimized speed of 10+ websites, achieved high SEO rank.

Computer Lecturer

Teacher

(15+ years) 06/2006 - (continued)

- Taught 2000+ students in web technologies courses, ICDL in 4 universities, vocational colleges, private classes.
- Created, published tens of hours of unique free web, office video tutorials, which has led to the acquisition of skills by thousands of Persian speakers around the world.

Volunteer work

DevOps and Front-End Developer

Khadije Charity Iran (4 years 4 months) 12/2017 - 03/2022

 Developed the website, all the software infrastructure, accelerated fulfill the wishes of 110,000+ people.

Software Solutions for Business Expert

WorldSkills Iran Iran

(5 years 4 months) 06/2010 - 08/2015

 Tutored, train three talents who won silver, two bronze medals in national competitions; Held the national team camp to attend WorldSkills Sao Paulo 2015.

Languages

English Fluent C1

Persian Native

Education

M.S. in IT Management

Azad University Tehran, Iran 2015 - 2022

B.S. in Computer Software Engineering

Azad University Nour, Iran 2008 - 2014

Skills



Fully Proficient Web Technology HTML, CSS, JavaScript, PHP Language C, C++, C#, VB.NET, Node.js, TypeScript, Python, Bash

Data Structure and Database MySQL, SQL Server, JSON, YAML

Web Service SOAP, RESTful API, GraphQL

Back-end PHP Web Framework Laravel, Symfony

Frontend JS Library Alpine.js, React, Vue.js, Angular, jQuery

CSS Framework Tailwind, Bootstrap, Semantic UI, Materialize

Build Tool Sass, Grunt, Gulp, Gradle, Webpack

Test-driven development - TDD PHPUnit

CI/CD Container Docker, Kubernetes

Backend Web Server Nginx, Apache

Server Configuration Framework, UI cPanel, DirectAdmin

Software Development Methodology Scrum, Agile, Kanban

OS Windows, Ubuntu, Debian, CentOS, macOS, VMware ESXi

Microsoft Office Specialist Word, Excel, Access, PowerPoint, VBA

Graphic Design Tool Photoshop, Illustrator, InDesign, Figma

Awards and Honors

Medallion for Excellence

WorldSkills Iran - IT Software Applications

Membership	Iran
National Elites Foundation	2013
The Best Corporate, Tourism Website 5th Iran Web Festival	Iran <i>2012</i>
Silver Medal	Yazd, Iran
WorldSkills Iran - IT Software Solutions for Business	2009

Mashhad, Iran

2008